A Finding Aid to the America: Now and Here Records, circa 2010-2012, in the Archives of American Art AAA.amernowh
Archives of American Art
America: Now and Here records
circa 2010-2012
AAA.amernowh
Archives of American Art
0.9 Linear feet
The records of America: Now and Here, a traveling arts program headquartered in New York City that provided traveling arts presentations, measure 0.9 linear feet and date from circa 2010-2012. The collection consists of interviews with artists and poets, two writings, and printed material, much relating to the America: Now and Here program in Kansas City (2011 May). The materials were designed to create interactive dialogues with visitors about the "American Journey," our culture, the arts, and creativity.
America: Now and Here, circa 2010-2011.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The America: Now and Here records were donated to the Archives of American Art in 2012 by Dorothy Dunn, former Director of the organization.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requrires advance notice.
Historical Note
America: Now and Here, a privately funded project, was founded by artist Eric Fischl with Dorothy Dunn as Director. Its mission was to provide a multi-disciplinary art experience that would travel from cities to small towns, encouraging dialogues among ordinary Americans about issues of importance to this country. Included in the program were visual art exhibitions, plays, movies, music, poetry, and inter-active exercises with an emphasis on young people's participation. More than 150 artists were involved with the program. Mobile truck visual art exhibitions would be situated with performance space and retail shops, driving economic activity in participating regions. The exhibitions traveled to Chicago, Detroit, Kansas City, Baltimore, Aspen and other venues. The program was suspended in 2012 due to lack of funds.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 4 series.
Series 1: Interviews, circa 2010 (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 2: Writings, 2010-2011 (Box 1; 2 folders)
Series 3: Printed Material, circa 2010-2012 (Boxes 1-2, OV 3; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 4: Artwork, circa 2010 (Box 2; 1 folder)
Scope and Contents note
The records of America: Now and Here, a traveling arts program headquartered in New York City that provided traveling arts presentations, measure 0.9 linear feet and date from circa 2010-2012. The collection consists of interviews with artists and poets, two writings, and printed material, much relating to the America: Now and Here program in Kansas City (2011 May). The materials were designed to create interactive dialogues with visitors about the "American Journey," our culture, the arts, and creativity.
Dunn, Dorothy; Fischl, Eric, 1948-; Artists and community; Community arts projects; Interviews; Traveling exhibitions
- Interviews, circa 2010; Series 1; 0.3 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Poets and artists from various disciplines were interviewed by America: Now and Here. Many of the interviews were conducted by Eugene Michael Santiago, but numerous transcripts do not identifiy the interviewer. Some well-known interview subjects include program founder Eric Fischl, playright Edward Albee, visual artists Julian Schnabel and Bill Viola, various poets including Billie Collins and lesser known individuals. Subjects discussed include the meaning of "the American Journey," the development of the artist, sources of inspiration and work, and the relationship between art and culture.
  - Artists, A-D, Transcripts, circa 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Artists, E-K, Transcripts, circa 2010; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Artists, L-P, Transcripts, circa 2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Artists, R-W, Transcripts, circa 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Poets, B-Ma, Transcripts, circa 2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Poets, Me-W, Transcripts, circa 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Writings, 2010-2011; Series 2; 2 Folders Box 1
  The project "Crossing State Lines, An American Renga" created a collaborative poem written by 54 American poets and was edited by Bob Holman and Carl Muske-Dukes. The renga concept is based on the Japanese "renga," or "conversation" poem, and was chosen to link the work of poets from across the country. Each poet wrote two five-line sequences.
  "Give Away," a scene written by Matt Spicer, is based on a dream of Julie Norton and includes an artist's statement explaining the piece.
  - "Crossing State Lines, An American Renga," Manuscript and Published Version, 2011; Includes 1 videodisc (DVD) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Give Away" by Matt Spicer, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Printed Material, circa 2010-2012; Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, OV 3
  This series includes a large quantity of promotional material explaining the program's mission and components. Also included are posters, interactive materials related to the "Make-a-Mask" activity, and postcards to which visitors would respond. Miscellaneous items include fund raising materials, staff badges, a catalog, and a workbook prepared for children and family participation. Much of this series refers to the Kansas City program (2011 May).
  - Clippings, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Posters, undated; circa 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in OV 3.
  - Presentation Materials, circa 2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes 1 videodisc (DVD); oversized material housed in OV 3.
  - Press Materials, circa 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Program Postcards, Blank, circa 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Program Poscards with Responses, circa 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Items, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Posters (from Box 1, Folder 10), circa 2011 (Box OV 3)
  - Oversized Presentation Materials (from Box 2, Folder 1), circa 2011 (Box OV 3)
- Artwork, circa 2010; Series 4; 1 Folders Box 2
  Artwork consists of a wicker and feather horn decorated with swatches of brightly colored fabric.
  - Feathered Horn by Unidentified Artist, circa 2010 (Box 2, Folder 7)